A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Office and Home Files FA1353
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Office and Home Files
1888-2010
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Rockefeller, Mary French (1910-1997)
FA1353
176.45 Cubic Feet 419 containers.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted in accordance with the 2009 donation of the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing audiovisual materials (VHS, audio cassettes) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact a RAC archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title. Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Arrangement
Original order, as received. The material was significantly disorganized, originating from closets, cabinets, and other storage areas. To enhance access, this finding aid is arranged into three subgroups:
Personal Papers and Interests, SG 1; Art, SG 2; Projects and Properties, SG 3.
Within each subgroup, the records are loosely arranged in series by primary subject/topic or property/location as applicable.
Scope and Contents
The Laurance S. Rockefeller Office and Home Files are comprised of records received by the Rockefeller Archive Center from several of Laurance S. Rockefeller's homes and residences, primarily including 834 Fifth Avenue in New York City, and Kent House in Pocantico Hills, NY. Select files were also received from other properities such as Woodstock, VT; Hawaii; and the U.S. Virgin Islands.
The collection also contains a variety of files created and maintained by the staff of the Rockefeller family office, Room 5600, Rockefeller Center, New York City, many of which may have been brought home, or transported back and forth to a residence by either Laurance S. or Mary French Rockefeller or their staff.
Files document: LSR and Rockefeller family correspondence and activities; LSR biographical materials, awards, and speeches; art and estate files; a variety of Mary French Rockefeller and Laurance S. Rockefeller personal and philanthropic interests such as: LSR Fund, MSKCC, and YWCA; as well as meomrial serivce files.
Properties documented primarily include those in: New York City; Pocantico Hills; Woodstock, VT; Wyoming; the Virgin Islands and Rockresorts.
- Personal Papers and Interests, 1888-2010; 1; 118.83 Cubic Feet 281 containers.
  - Biographical Materials, Awards, Speeches and Remarks, 1910-2010; 1_1
    - LSR - Biography, 1972-1990 (Box 26, Folder 6, Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - LSR - Charitable Giving - General (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Charitable Giving - LSR Charitable Trust, 1988-1989 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Chase Note - $8 MM Line, 1994-2003 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Contributions, 1987-1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Donations - Estate, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Congressional Gold Medal, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Interview - Edith Hansen Interview re David Milton Book, 1991 January 17 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Miscellaneous, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - LSR - Personal Data Articles, Gifts, 1960-1990 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Political Contributions, 1988-1999 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - LSR - Contributions - Public Announcements of, 1983-1987 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Public Relations - General, 1980-2000 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Public Relations - Winks Biography - General, 1993-1999 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Public Relations - Winks Biography - Publicity Issues, 1997-1998 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Public Relations - Winks Biography - Revised Edition, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Public Relations - Winks Biography - Winks Manuscript, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Public Relations - Winks Biography - Contract, Island Press, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Quotes, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Special Funding Projects - Giverny Project, 1989-1990 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Speech File, 1934-1986 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - LSR - UFOs - General, 1996-2002 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Tax Issues, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted - LSR Estate - Open in 2029
    - LSR - The Antique Company of New York, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - LSR - Tax Return - 2004 - Draft (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Who's Who, 1988-1990 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - LSR - Notes - Objectives, Challenges, and Achievements, 1983; 1984 (Box 76, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes LSR underlining.
    - LSR - Awards - British Virgin Islands Belonger Ceremony, 2003 September 26 (Box 76, Folder 4)
      LSR letter announcing 2-year transitional program to BVI Officials, 8/1/2003. Letters of response from BVI officials. Letter from the Chief Minister announcing Belonger Status, 9/12/2003. List of Guests, Program, and LSR's Words of Acceptance, 9/26/2003. Belonger Certificate and ID card. press releases, LSR statement for press release. LSR Letters of Appreciation. BVI Belonger Ceremony items sent to Archives, 10/9/2003. Speeches and background material.
    - LSR - Speeches - Grand Teton National Park Fiftieth Anniversary, 2000 (Box 76, Folder 5)
      Speeches with background material.
    - LSR - Speeches - Governor's Preservation and Parks Award, 1997 December 13 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Speeches - Grand Steward of the Tetons Award, 1997 September 10 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Speeches - Henry L. Diamond Remarks on Fortieth Anniversary of the Virgin Islands National Park, 1996 December 11 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - LSR and David Rockefeller Birthday Celebration (80th and 75th), 1990 June 15 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - LSR - Speeches - LSR Testimony at Nelson A. Rockefeller Vice Presidential Nomination Hearings, 1974 December 4 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - LSR - Speeches - Marsh Billings Rockefeller National Historical Park Hearings, 1992 June 2 (Box 77, Folder 1)
      Hearing before the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands, House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs. Speeches with background material.
    - LSR - Speeches - Woodrow Wilson Award Speech, Princeton University, 1991 February 16 (Box 77, Folder 2)
      Speeches with background material. Includes transcription of audio tapes.
    - LSR - Speeches - Congressional Gold Medal Award and Acceptance, 1990 May 17 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Awards - Medal of Freedom awarded by President Lyndon Baines Johnson, 1969 January 20 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Speeches - Notification of Appointment as Commander of the British Empire (Hon.), 1971 June 14 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Winks Biography - LSR Background, 1990s (Box 78, Folder 3)
      Laurance S. Rockefeller: Catalyst for Conservation, by Robin W. Winks.
    - LSR - Winks Biography - General, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Winks Biography - LSR Personal Distribution, 1998 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Winks Biography - LSR Inscriptions, 1997-1999 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Winks Biography - LSR Accompanying Letters, 1997-1998 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Winks Biography - Distribution Lists, 1997-1998 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - LSR and MFR - Magazine Articles on, 1963-2003 (Box 92, Folder 7-8, Box 96, Folder 1-2)
      Town and Country, 1992 October (Woodstock article); National Geographic Traveler, 2000 November-December (Grand Tetons article); National Geographic: 1963 December (YWCA: International Success Story, MFR's trip), 1967 January (Parks, Plans, and People, LSR & MFR South America trip), 1974 December (Problems in Paradise, LSR & MFR Pacific Islands journey), 1992 February (opening of Marsh-Billings National Historical Park in Woodstock, with photo of LSR and MFR), and others.
    - MSKCC - Bessie Dashiell - LSR Remarks, 2002 December 15 (Box 102, Folder 9)
      LSR remarks presenting Bessie Dashiell books at Rockefeller Family Christmas Luncheon
    - MSKCC - Bessie Dashiell - Draft and Published Book, 2002 (Box 103, Folder 1)
      Fred Smith's draft of Bessie Dashiell, and copy of published book.
    - LSR - National Park Service - Medal - 75 Years of Service, 1916-1991., 2 medals (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Biographies, 1970-2004 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Awards and Affiliations, 1981-1993 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Awards - Presidential Medal of Freedom - LSR Citation, 1969 January 20 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Photographs - LSR - Youth and Young Man (Koshiba), 1949 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Diary (copy), 1926 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Princeton University - Senior Thesis, 1932 (Box 104, Folder 7)
      The Concept of value and Its Relation to Ethics
    - LSR - Family Correspondence (including Parents), 1920s-1989 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Letter to Her Sons, 1967 August 16 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - LSR and MFR - Dogs (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - LSR - Favorite Songs (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - LSR - Interview with Wyatt Rockefeller, 1993 April 27 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - LSR - Statement on Influences, 1997 January 22 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - LSR - Guggenheim Interview - Transcript, 1992 February 20 (Box 104, Folder 14)
      Transcription of LSR interview with Charles Guggenheim for A Place in the Land.
    - LSR - Background Material - WGBH Interview, 1998 July 29 (Box 104, Folder 14A)
      LSR background material selected by LSR for the Interview for the WGBH film on the Rockefeller Family, July 29, 1998.
    - LSR - Background Material, 1967-2006 (Box 105, Folder 1)
      Assorted material on LSR's career.
    - Castro, Nash - Statements about LSR - Conservationist, 2002 November (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - MSKCC - LSR - Oral Histories, 1994-1995 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - MSKCC - Directory of Officers and Board Members, 2004 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI) - Resolution on LSR's Election as Chairman Emeritus, 1996 November 15 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Gold Medal - ACA/JHPI Resolution of Appreciation, 1991 October 10-11 (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Princeton University - Center for Human Values - Presentation to LSR, 1991 October 25 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      Bound copy of LSR's Senior Thesis, presented to LSR for the Inauguration of the University Center for Human Values, Princeton.
    - Princeton University - Birthday Presentation to LSR, 2004 May 26 (Box 106, Folder 4)
      Bound copy of Laurance S. Rockefeller '32 and Princeton, presented to LSR on his 94th birthday. Record of LSR's Support and Gifts to Princeton.
    - LSR - Speech File, 1941-1996 (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Reader's Digest, 1993 (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - LSR - Biography - Statement of Influences, 1997 January 22 (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - LSR - Biography - Background for New Book Project, 1978-2000 (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - LSR - Biography - Quotations, 2009 (Box 140, Folder 11)
      Quotations selected for the Venrock Fortieth Anniversary Book.
    - LSR - Biography - New Biography Project, 2000 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Biography and Background Material, 2000s (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Princeton University - Fujita Painting, 2008-2009 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Quotations - From LSR (Box 157, Folder 8)
    - LSR - Quotations - LSR's Favorites (Box 157, Folder 9-10)
    - LSR - Quotations - about LSR (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - LSR - Quotations (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Induction to National Recreation and Park Hall of Fame, 2009 November (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Diaries, 1938-1969 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Diaries, 1970-1982 (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Diaries - Handwritten Notes (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Greek/English New Testament - Inscribed to LSR - On his Visit to the Athens YMCA, 1963 February 23 (Box 163, Folder 2)
    - LSR - First Draft of "At Sunrise Every Soul is Born Again" (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Affiliations, 1958-1993 (Box 164, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Awards, 1950-2004 (Box 165, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Remarks - Rockefeller Family Christmas Luncheon, Pocantico, 1997 (Box 167, Folder 6)
      Hosted by Sharon and Jay Rockefeller and Family.
    - LSR - Quotations - Assorted (Box 167, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Pistol License, 1969 (Box 167, Folder 8)
    - MSKCC - "A Tribute to LSR"- Donation to MSKCC Library, 2010 May (Box 167, Folder 9)
      Letter from Greg Kachejian, manager of the Patients' Library at MSKCC, re: donating package of A Tribute to Laurance S. Rockefeller to the Library.
    - LSR - Congressional Gold Medal - Remarks by the President, 1991 September 27 (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University - General, 2000-2007 (Box 184, Folder 11)
    - Princeton University - Fujita Gift, 1996-1999 (Box 184, Folder 12)
    - Princeton University - LSR Gift of 5 Million Dollars, 1996 (Box 184, Folder 13)
    - MFR-LSR - Awards, 1964-1999 (Box 199, Folder 4)
    - MFR-LSR - Awards - Photos, 1964-1999 (Box 199, Folder 5)
    - Fred Smith Biography of LSR - Drafts and Manuscript, 1970s-2004 (Box 200, Folder 1-2)
    - Fred Smith Biography of LSR - LSR Scrapbook, 1910-1980s (Box 200, Folder 3)
    - LSR Interview, 1993 July 27 (Box 205, Folder 1)
      Interviewed by Fraser Seitel
    - LSR Interview, 1993 August 17 (Box 205, Folder 2)
    - LSR Interview, 1993 October 13 (Box 205, Folder 3)
    - LSR Interview, 1993 November 18 (Box 205, Folder 4)
    - LSR Interview, 1993 December 16 (Box 205, Folder 5)
    - LSR Interview, 1994 January 24 (Box 205, Folder 6)
    - LSR Interview, 1994 March 30 (Box 205, Folder 7)
    - LSR Interview - Lewis Book, 1994 April 28 (Box 205, Folder 8)
    - LSR - Club Membership Handbooks, 1991-2006 (Box 205, Folder 9, Box 206, Folder 1-4)
    - LSR - Princeton Papers and Lecture Notes, 1930s (Box 251, Folder 4-6, Box 252, Folder 3-6, Box 253, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Lincoln School Books (Box 253, Folder 2, Box 254, Box 255, Box 256, Box 257)
    - LSR - Harvard Law Notebooks - Class of 1936 (Box 408, Folder 3-4, Box 409, Folder 1-3, Box 410, Folder 1-2)
    - LSR - Harvard Law - Review Notes - Class of 1936 (Box 410, Folder 3-4, Box 411, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Quotations Collected by LSR, 1930-1984 (Box 283, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Biography, 1986-1991 (Box 301, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Biography - Conservation and Preservation, 1933-1993 (Box 301, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Biography - Conservation and Preservation - Events - Remarks, 1948-1991 (Box 301, Folder 3-4)
    - LSR - Conrad L. Wirth - "The Other Brother - Notes on the Life and Times of John D. Rockefeller's Third Grandson", 1979 (Box 326, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Awards - MSKCC - Naming of the Laurance S. Rockefeller Outpatient Pavilion (53rd Street), 1999 April 19 (Box 329, Folder 3, Box 330, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Awards - Salute to Living Landmarks (Landmarks Conservancy), 2001 November 7 (Box 329, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Awards - The Carnegie Medal of Philanthropy, 2001 December 10 (Box 329, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Awards - MSKCC - Awards for Excellence, 1999 May 18 (Box 329, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Awards - ACA and JHPI Resolution - Congressional Gold Medal, 1991 October 10-11 (Box 330, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Awards - MSKCC - Congressional Gold Medal, 1997 December 16 (Box 330, Folder 4)
    - NAR and Happy Rockefeller - New York Cancer Society Gala, 1963 (Box 330, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Awards - Duke University - Honorary Doctorate - Bible, 1981 May 10 (Box 330, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Membership and ID Cards (Box 333, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Awards - 834 Fifth Avenue Corporation - The 834 Vase, 1989-1990 (Box 336, Folder 3)
    - LSR - 834 Fifth Avenue - LSR Flower Gifts and Messages, 1997-2004 (Box 336, Folder 4-5)
    - LSR - Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center, 1991 (Box 338, Folder 3)
    - LSR - Dinner Honoring Winston Churchill, at the Waldorf Astoria, 1946 March 15 (Box 338, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Pamphlet - Cause of the Present Depression and Possible Remedies, Speech by Winthrop W. Aldrich, 1933 February 22 (Box 338, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Silver Trowel used in laying cornerstone of Rockefeller Center's new Time and Life Building, 1959 June 23 (Box 342, Folder 2)
      Presented to LSR
    - LSR - Awards - MFR and LSR - National Parks Foundation, 1993 (Box 403, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Awards - MFR and LSR, 2004 (Box 403, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Awards - USS Theodore Roosevelt CUN-71 - Honorary Plank Owner, 1986 October 25 (Box 404, Folder 1)
  - Mary French Rockefeller and Family Files, 1888-2008; 1_2
    - MFR - Estate - General, 1997-2001 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - MFR - Estate - Certificate of Cremation, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - MFR - Estate - Chase Trust, 1997-2000 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - MFR - Death Certificate, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Gifts to Family and Family Trusts, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - MFR - Remarks - Spelman Weekend, 1980 May 10-11 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - MFR - Remarks - World Mercy Fund, 1981 September 25 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - MFR - Remarks - YWCA - Chicago - Fund for the Future, 1977-1984 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - MFR - Remarks - YWCA Luncheon - Salute to Women Achievers, 1983 November 3 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - MFR - Estate - Legatee Letters, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - MFR - Estate - Living Will, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - MFR - Estate - Tax Return, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - MFR - Estate - Woodstock Items, 1997 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - MFR - Estate - Trust - Elizabeth M. Billings, 2000 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - General, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Acknowledgment Cards, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Family Service, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Guest List, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Invitations, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Programs, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Acknowledgment Cards (unsigned), 1997 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Meeting Agendas, Task Lists, Logistics, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Obituary, Public Relations, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Burial, 1994-1995 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - Reception, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - MFR - Memorial Service - YWCA - MFR Memorial Contributions, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - MFR - Montana Mineral Rights (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French - General, 1927-1996 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - LSR and Mary French Rockefeller - Marriage License (copy), 1934 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Correspondence - JDR Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (copies), 1928-1934 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      Copies of LSR letters to AAR and JDR JR.
    - LSR - Senior Thesis, Princeton University, 1932 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Lincoln School, 1928-1994 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      Materials include some LSR underlining
    - Rockefeller Family - Correspondence, 1952-1986 (Box 75, Folder 5-6)
    - Maze, Etienne - Letter to LSR, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Rockefeller Family - Articles on, 1960s-1990s (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell - Draft Copies and Book, 2002 December (Box 77, Folder 6-7)
    - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell - Copy of Death Certificate, 2002 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell - Responses, 2003 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell - Distribution, 2002-2003 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell - Buckslips - Printing, 2002-2003 (Box 78, Folder 2A)
    - LSR Family Photo Album, 1954 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French - Biographies, 1993-1997 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - LSR and MFR - Marriage License (copy), 1934 July 28 (Box 104, Folder 4)
      Woodstock.
    - Rockefeller, Mary French - Sing-A-Long Songbook (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French - Assorted Clippings (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Rockefeller, Mary French - Photos, 1990s (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Art - "Appeal to the Great Spirit" - Cyrus Dallin, 2001-2003 (Box 109, Folder 2)
      Sculpture
    - LSR Family - Thanksgiving, 2003 (Box 109, Folder 3)
      Family festivities.
    - YWCA - World YWCA, 2006-2008 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI): Report and Proposal on Filing for JHPI, 1957 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc. (JHPI) - 50th Anniversary Book, 1940-1990 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - LSR - UFO Research Coalition - Briefing Document, 1995 (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Fund for the Advancement of the Human Spirit - Tribute to LSR, 1993 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell - Fred Smith Copy (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - LSR - Charitable Lead Trusts, 1988-1989 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - LSR - Gifts to Grandchildren, 1988-1991 (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Use of LSR Name, 1994-1997 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - LSR Estate - Laura Chasin Sale of Items to Family, 2005 June (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - LSR Estate - Book Appraisal and LSR Family Selection, 2005 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - LSR Estate - Log of Donations to Organizations, 2004-2005 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Art Production Fund - Yvonne Force Villareal, 1995-1999 (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - LSR - Intervivos Trust - Sherman Howe - Closing, 1999 (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - LSR - Gifts - Presents and Donations (Box 137)
      Ledger
    - LSR - Gifts - Transfer Binder (Box 137)
    - LSR-MFR - Wedding - Sixtieth Anniversary - LSR Remarks, 1994 August 15 (Box 157, Folder 3)
      LSR handwritten notes for remarks.
    - Waletzky, Jacob - Toast to LSR, 2000 June 17 (Box 157, Folder 4)
      Rockefeller Family Weekend, Pocantico. Joint birthday celebration for LSR (90) and David Rockefeller (85).
    - Waletzky, Jacob - LSR's Thoughts on, 2001 May (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Waletzky, Jacob - LSR Prayer for, 2001 May 24 (Box 157, Folder 6)
      Family luncheon.
    - Waletzky, Jacob Peter, 1992-2002 (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - LSR - Legacy of Bessie Dashiell (Box 158, Folder 1)
      Copy of original publication, marked "FS" (Fred Smith).
    - MFR - Childhood Notebook and Diaries, 1988; 1989; 1993; undated (Box 162, Folder 2)
    - "Memoirs of David Meriwether Milton" - LSR Underlinings (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr, Founder of Rockefeller Center", 1961 (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - MFR - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 167, Folder 10)
    - LSR-MFR - Christmas Card List (Card Index) (Box 168, Box 169)
    - LSR-MFR - Corporation and Individual Gifts (Card Index) (Box 169, Box 170)
    - MFR - National Board YWCA (Card Index) (Box 170)
    - MFR - World Service Council Members (Card Index) (Box 170)
    - MFR - Camping City - YWCA (Card Index) (Box 170)
    - Family Christmas Luncheon - Spiritual Insights, 1995 December 17 (Box 167, Folder 16)
      The Playhouse, Pocantico Hills. Hosted by LSR and MFR.
    - Family Christmas Luncheon - LSR Packet - with Welcoming Remarks, 1995 December 17 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - LSR Family - Invitation to Family Christmas Luncheon, 2002 December 15 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - LSR Family - Children's Program for Family Christmas Luncheon, 2002 December 15 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - LSR - Christmas/Holiday Card - George and Laura Bush (President and First Lady), 2001 (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - LSR-MFR - Christmas/Holiday Cards Collection Book, 1940s-1997 (Box 341, Folder 2)
    - MFR-LSR - Christmas/Holiday Cards - Received, 1942-1945 (Box 242, Folder 1)
    - MFR-LSR - Christmas/Holiday Cards - Received, 1949 (Box 242, Folder 2)
    - MFR - Christmas/Holiday Cards - Received, 1952 (Box 377, Folder 2)